<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cosmo -Personal Blog</title>
    <description>A blog about managing social activities and with coding life and activities</description>
    <link>http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 13:03:13 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 13:03:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are you a geek or a nerd?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Think you’re a geek? Then you’d probably be offended if someone called you a nerd. Got nerd-pride? Then you probably look at geek culture as nothing more than glorified hipsterism. Think there isn’t a real difference between the two?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh brother, are you in for a rude awakening! Read below and discover just how wrong you are about the 4 main differences between geeks and nerds!
1) Interests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to differentiate a geek from a nerd is by taking a look at their respective interests. The term “geek” has become associated with someone who has a vested interest in one particular thing and knows it on an expert level. While it isn’t uncommon for them to have more than one interest, there’s always one subject that takes precedence over the others. Nerds, on the other hand, concern themselves with academics such as math and science. As a result, they enjoy games of strategy (e.g. Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons) or watch television shows (e.g. Star Trek) that share this complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Attire&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerds have always been of the conservative mindset when it comes to their clothing of choice: slacks, button down shirts, and dress shoes are some of this species’ favorites. As for eyewear, nerds don actual prescription glasses out of necessity and not to make an ironic or geeky fashion statement. Geeks, meanwhile, want their clothes to be a reflection of their interests. Sneakers, jeans, and a graphic tee featuring a cartoon, movie, or other intellectual property they enjoy is standard. However, geeks can sometimes be slovenly, tending to their interests more than… ehem… hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Future Occupations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right, even geeks and nerds need to make a living, but their career choices couldn’t be anymore disparate from each other. Geeks tend to gravitate toward jobs that let them indulge in their interests and use their obscure expertise on a particular subject for a more practical purpose. Ultimately, geeks want to have fun while they work, so it’s not surprising that they become writers, graphic artists, or animators. Nerds seek jobs that benefit from their devotion to all things academia. As such, they end up in fields with a focus on the applied sciences like computer programmers, scientists, and professional abacus builders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Social Interaction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interests of nerds and geeks have an impact on how they interact with others in a social setting. Since not many people share an appreciation for equations and scientific theory, nerds can sometimes be introverted and by extension not know how to respond appropriately in conversation. It’s because of this that nerds have a tendency to keep to themselves or seek the company of others that share complex and academic interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While geeks are shown to react better to social stimuli, their interests can also wreak havoc—and they may not even realize it. Due to passion for the subject, geeks can go off at length about their favorite comic, movie, or obscure early 1980s movie rock musical, leaving those that do not understand it out of the conversation and eventually bored. And, like we said before, the geek may be oblivious to these visual cues and continue to talk about the minute details of the fact that Brian DePalma’s true masterwork was the underrated musical Phantom of the Paradise that took the classic Phantom of the Opera story and transplanted it to the modern day record industry, thus making a strong statement about… hey… where are you guys going?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;Credits &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sparknotes.com/mindhut/2012/12/18/the-4-main-differences-between-geeks-and-nerds&quot;&gt;SPARKNOTES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 13:45:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/Are-you-a-geek-%3F-or-a-nird</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/Are-you-a-geek-%3F-or-a-nird</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why do you need to be social!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Social….Social…Social..The mentality is that nerds and geeks are not meant to be social, An engineering manager told me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I would never hire an extremely introverted individual and don&#39;t even know how one would make it past the interview.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a programmer, you do spend a lot of time off on your own, but you’re not totally in a bubble or anything.  You’re frequently collaborating with other developers, support staff etc.  If you don’t have good social skills, those collaborations won’t be as good, and you’re less likely to advance quickly or sometimes even perform well (depending on the nature of your job and how you interact).
That said, there’s a huge difference between “introverted” and “poor social skills”.  I’m very introverted, and I’m a developer, but my social skills aren’t too bad.  My nature isn’t to seek out other people, but when I need to collaborate, I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By contrast, there are those that are condescending, rude, etc., and don’t communicate.  They won’t warn you when they made a change that might affect you, or when they altered your code to “be more efficient”.  Those types of behaviors can make someone very difficult to work with, and aren’t tied to introversion at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to act appropriately to your job function.  Whether or not you’re an introvert is pretty irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an extrovert helps in a few areas, but it’s not really all that necessary.  It’ll help you convince your higher-ups that you should be allowed to go ahead with your POC, or something similar.  It’ll also help your personal relationships with the rest of your team (although I don’t think it’ll make you work all that much more effectively).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 11:03:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/Why-do-you-need-to-be-social!!!!</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/Why-do-you-need-to-be-social!!!!</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to cosmo blog, am not really a blog type of person but i just decided to start writing about what people like me really need to overcome there greatest distraction&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;NOTE: THIS WEBSITE WAS CODED ON A FRAMEWORK CALLLED JEKYLL A RUBY BASED PLATFORM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to pick jekyll because am not a lazy programmer and i love doing things the hard way of cause there are easier way to write blogs i mean very easy ways, but we as programmers are meant to do things our own way and leave the other ways of blogging to those who can’t code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 06:03:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/introduction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.cosmo.com/cosmo/introduction</guid>
        
        
        <category>nill</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
